A Register of the Ivan Alekseevich Poliakov Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Ivan Alekseevich Poliakov Papers
1942-1969
2008C66
Hoover Institution Archives
39 microfilm reels (5.85 linear feet)
These papers contain the correspondence, and writings of Ivan Alekseevich Poliakov, participant in the Don Cossack uprising of 1918, and ataman of the Don Cossacks in emigration since 1947.
Poliakov, Ivan Alekseevich
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
A portion of the collection is available on Microfilm
Location of Original Materials
Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary, Jordanville, New York
Chronology
1886 August 10 Born, Russia
1914 Graduated, Nikolaevskoe inzhenernoe uchilishche
1915 Captain, Ninth Army
1918 Arrived at the Don, joined Ataman P. N. Krasnov's Don Cossack Army
1919 Emigrated to Serbia
1947 Assigned as acting ataman of Don Cossacks
1952 Emigrated to the U.S.A.
1959 Author, Krasnov-Vlasov: vospominaniia
1962 Author, Donskie kazaki v bor'be s bol'shevikami
1969 Died, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers contain the correspondence, and writings of Ivan Alekseevich Poliakov, participant in the Don Cossack uprising of 1918, and ataman of the Don Cossacks in emigration since 1947. The Correspondence file includes detailed correspondence with leading Russian émigré military and social leaders, and provides a rich source of information on the activities of Cossack activities in the diaspora.
Poliakov's Speeches and writings include the typescript of Donskie kazaki v bor'be s bol'shevikami, as well as related correspondence and reviews. In addition, several articles, notes, speeches, and materials relating to Poliakov's monograph Krasnov-Vlasov: vospominaniia are included.
The Subject file includes materials on the history of the Don and Kuban Cossacks, the Russkii obshche-voinskii soiuz, and General A. A. Vlasov. Of special significance are documents relating to the Don Cossack ataman elections in the diaspora.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register. Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into five series: Biographical file, Correspondence, Speeches and writings, Subject file, Miscellany, and Photographs
Related Material
Sviatoslav Varlaamovich Denisov Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Petr Nikolaevich Donskov Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Nicholas V. Feodoroff Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Petr Nikolaevich Krasnov Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Russkii obshche-voinskii soiuz (ROVS) Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Biography
Ivan Alekseevich Poliakov was born into a Don Cossack family in Novocherkassk on August 10, 1886. His officer father sent Ivan to Donskoi kadetskii korpus, after which he went on to the Nikolaevskoe inzhenernoe uchilishche, graduating in 1914. Poliakov served in the Ninth Army as captain, joining General Petr N. Krasnov’s Don Cossack Army in 1917 and being elevated to the rank of major general in 1918. Poliakov immigrated to Serbia in 1919. He returned to active military life during General Krasnov’s involvement in organizing Cossack divisions within the German Army from 1942 to 1945; unlike Krasnov, however, Poliakov joined Vlasov’s Russkaia osvoboditel’naia armiia.
Poliakov was elected Don Cossack ataman in 1947, a position he continued to hold through 1965. Arriving in the United States in 1952, he published two memoirs, one dealing with the Don Cossack anti-Bolshevist struggle from 1917 to 1920 and another on General Krasnov’s and General Vlasov’s activities during World War II. He died in New York in 1969.
American Committee for the Liberation of the Peoples of Russia..; Vlasov, Andrei Andreevich, 1901-1946.; Cossacks--History.; Don Cossacks in emigration.; Russia. Armiia. Kubanskoe kazach'e voisko.; Russkii Obshche-Voinskii Soiuz.; World War, 1939-1945--Personal narratives.
- Biographical file, 1950-1969 and undated. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Address book, biographical sketch, congratulatory addresses, family correspondence, financial documents, identification documents, medical records
  - Address book, undated (Folder 1: 1)
  - Biographical sketch, undated (Folder 1: 2)
  - Congratulatory addresses, 1965 and undated (Folder 1: 3)
  - Family correspondence, 1952-1969 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Financial documents, 1956-1966 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Identification documents, 1950-1952 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Medical documents, 1967-1968 and undated (Folder 1: 7)
- Correspondence, 1942-1969 and undated.
  Cards and letters, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - Unidentified
    - Undated (Folder 1: 8)
    - 1944-1949 (Folder 1: 9)
    - 1950-1954 (Folder 1: 10)
    - 1960-1969 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Abesin, A., 1953-1955 (Folder 1: 12)
  - Abragamsen, K., 1955 (Folder 1: 13)
  - Abramenkova, Sofiia Petrovna, 1963 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Abramov, Fedor Fedorovich, 1942-1962 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Abramov, Petr Fedorovich, 1952-1963 and undated (Folder 1: 16)
  - Afanas'ev, A. E., 1962 (Folder 1: 17)
  - Agafonov, Ivan Trifonovich, 1959 (Folder 1: 18)
  - Agapov, Mikhail Nikitich, 1960 (Folder 1: 19)
  - Agoev, Konstantin Konstantinovich, 1953-1962 (Folder 1: 20)
  - Akintievskii, Konstantin Konstantinovich, undated (Folder 1: 21)
  - Akilokhvadi, Aleksandr Vladimirovich, 1960 (Folder 1: 22)
  - Aksenov, Sergei Serafimovich, 1952-1969 and undated (Folder 1: 23)
  - Aleksandrovskii, Sergei Borisovich, 1957-1966 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Alekseev, G., 1954 and undated. (Folder 2: 2)
    Includes Biulleten' rossiiskago tsentra antikommunistov v Avstralii
  - Alferov, Serafiim Zakhar'evich, 1962-1966 (Folder 2: 3)
  - American Committee for Liberation, 1960-1962. (Folder 2: 4)
    General note
    See also Sargeant, Howland
  - Anastasii (Gribanovskii), Metropolitan, 1952 (Folder 2: 5)
  - Anosov, Ivan Fomich, 1952-1955 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Antonov, Ivan Konstantinovich, 1952-1953 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Arkhangel'skii, Aleksei Petrovich, 1955 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Anufriev, P., 1960 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Artel, Zhanet, 1963 (Folder 2: 10)
  - Artemov, Timofei Mitrofanovich, 1949-1960 and undated (Folder 2: 11)
  - Astakhov, German Mikhailovich, 1953-1961 (Folder 2: 12)
  - Averkii (Taushev), Bishop, 1955-1956 (Folder 2: 13)
  - Azhogin, Vasilii Mikhailovich, 1952-1967 (Folder 2: 14)
  - Azhogina, Nataliia, 1953 (Folder 2: 15)
  - Badminov, N., 1957 (Folder 2: 16)
  - Baikalo, Sergei Nikolaevich, 1962 (Folder 2: 17)
  - Baikalov, A. V., 1950 (Folder 2: 18)
  - Baklanov, Evgenii, 1955-1956 (Folder 2: 19)
  - Baklanov, I., 1962 (Folder 2: 20)
  - Balabin, Evgenii Ivanovich, 1953-1967 (Folder 2: 21)
  - Balabin, Oleg Aleksandrovich
    - 1957-1960 (Folder 2: 22)
    - 1961 (Folder 2: 23)
    - 1962 (Folder 2: 24)
    - 1963-1969 (Folder 3: 1)
  - Balabina, Ekaterina Dragoliubovna, 1964 and undated (Folder 3: 2)
  - Baranov, A. F., undated (Folder 3: 3)
  - Baranov, Viacheslav, 1962 (Folder 3: 4)
  - Barskii, Konstantin Pavlovich, 1956-1962 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Basov, Nikolai Ivanovich, 1950-1964 (Folder 3: 6)
  - Bechinin, Igor, 1953 (Folder 3: 7)
  - Beliaeva, Sofiia Ivanovna, 1956 (Folder 3: 8)
  - Beliaevskii, Vasilii Arsen'evich
    - 1952-1959 (Folder 3: 9)
    - 1960-1966 (Folder 3: 10)
  - Belosel'skii, Sergei Sergeevich, 1952-1964 and undated (Folder 3: 11)
  - Belousov, Ivan Ivanovich, 1952-1959 (Folder 3: 12)
  - Belousov, Mikhail Andreevich, 1952-1954 (Folder 3: 13)
  - Belousova, Sofiia Sergeevna, 1952-1962 (Folder 3: 14)
  - Bel'kovich, E., 1964 (Folder 3: 15)
  - Bennigsen, Georgii Pavlovich, 1953 (Folder 3: 16)
  - Benzeman, Gleb Alekseevich, 1952-1958 (Folder 3: 17)
  - Birkin, Ivan Fedorovich, 1953-1963 (Folder 3: 18)
  - Bitin, I., 1952 (Folder 3: 19)
  - Blaise, Mikhail, 1960 (Folder 3: 20)
  - Bodrukhin, Aleksandr Alekseevich, 1952-1958 (Folder 3: 21)
  - Boichevskii, Aleksei Vasil'evich, 1953-1954 (Folder 3: 22)
  - Boldyrev, Oleg, Reverend, 1953-1954 (Folder 3: 23)
  - Bologov, Grigorii Kirillovich, 1952-1958 (Folder 4: 1)
  - Bolotovskii, Iulii Iul'evich, 1954-1955 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Boltov, Mr., 1950 (Folder 4: 3)
  - Bondarenko, Aleksandr Pavlovich, 1948 (Folder 4: 4)
  - Bondarenko, Il'ia Sergeevich, 1958 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Bondarenko, M., 1953 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Bondarenkov, N., 1953-1962 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Booth, Bill R., 1962 (Folder 4: 8)
  - Bordzilovskii, Anatolii Vikent'evich, 1957 (Folder 4: 9)
  - Borodin, Ivan Danilovich, 1960-1965 (Folder 4: 10)
  - Borodin, Nikolai Ivanovich, 1954 (Folder 4: 11)
  - Bozhenko, Nikolai and Mariia, 1954 (Folder 4: 12)
  - Bravin, Aleksandr Andreevich, 1962-1967 (Folder 4: 13)
  - Briditskii, V., 1954 (Folder 4: 14)
  - Brikin, Efim Fedorovich, 1953-1962 (Folder 4: 15)
  - Brykalin, Petr Mikhailovich, 1957-1966 and undated (Folder 4: 16)
  - Budankov, Petr, 1952-1954 and undated (Folder 4: 17)
  - Budberg, Nikolai, Baron, 1953 and undated (Folder 4: 18)
  - Budnyi, Aleksandr Semenovich, 1960 (Folder 4: 19)
  - Buguraev, Mikhail Konstantinovich, 1953 (Folder 4: 20)
  - Buguraev, Petr Viktorovich, 1952 (Folder 4: 21)
  - Buliubash, Evgenii Grigor'evich, 1960-1966 (Folder 4: 22)
  - Bul'kovich, E., 1963 (Folder 4: 23)
  - Bundesminister des Innern, 1956 (Folder 4: 24)
  - Burdin, Pavel, 1967 (Folder 4: 25)
  - Burkhinov, D., 1952 (Folder 4: 26)
  - Bus'ko, Petr Ivanovich, 1952-1953 (Folder 4: 27)
  - Butkov, Pavel Nikolaevich, 1965 (Folder 4: 28)
  - Buzin, Iakov Ivanovich, 1952-1953 (Folder 4: 29)
  - Bykadorov, Georgii Pavlovich, 1953 (Folder 4: 30)
  - Bylinskii, Mikhail Ivanovich, 1952-1965 (Folder 4: 31)
  - Byrnes, Ol'ga Nikolaevna, 1960 (Folder 4: 32)
  - Chekalova, Nataliia L., 1964 (Folder 4: 33)
  - Chekhov Publishing House, 1954-1956 (Folder 4: 34)
  - Cheremshanskii, Iurii Apollonovich, 1959-1967 (Folder 4: 35)
  - Cherepov, Aleksandr Nikolaevich, 1954-1963 and undated (Folder 4: 36)
  - Cherepov, Vladimir Aleksandrovich, 1963 (Folder 4: 37)
  - Cherkasov, Ivan Andreevich, 1952-1954 (Folder 4: 38)
  - Cherniavskii, Mikhail, 1953-1962 and undated (Folder 4: 39)
  - Chernoshchekov, V., 1954 (Folder 4: 40)
  - Chernyi, Sergei, 1953 (Folder 5: 1)
  - Chevichelov, Fedor, 1954-1962 (Folder 5: 2)
  - Chongov, Ivan Vasil'evich, 1952-1963 (Folder 5: 3)
  - Dadukin, S. A., 1956 (Folder 5: 4)
  - Dakhov, Nikolai Trofimovich, 1957-1965 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Dallin, Alexander, 1950-1951 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Danilevich, T., 1956 (Folder 5: 7)
  - Davydov, F., 1958 (Folder 5: 8)
  - Delianich, Ariadna Ivanovna, 1955-1966 (Folder 5: 9)
  - Demushkin, D., 1953 (Folder 5: 10)
  - Denisov, Sviatoslav Varlaamovich
    - 1947 (Folder 5: 11)
    - 1949
      - January-June (Folder 5: 12)
      - July-December (Folder 5: 13)
    - 1950 (Folder 5: 14)
    - 1951 (Folder 6: 1)
    - 1952-1954 (Folder 6: 2)
    - 1955-1956 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Denisova, Kseniia Vasil'evna, 1952-1954 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Denisova, Zoia Aleksandrovna, 1957-1958 (Folder 6: 5)
  - Diterikhs, Iuliia, 1953 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Dimitriev, Nikolai Vasil'evich, 1960 (Folder 6: 7)
  - Diubing, Mr., undated (Folder 6: 8)
  - Dmitriev, A. A., 1961-1964 and undated (Folder 6: 9)
  - Dolgopolov, Aleksandr Fedorovich, 1961-1964 (Folder 6: 10)
  - Dolgov, N., 1953-1958 (Folder 6: 11)
  - Dombrovskii, V., 1954-1963 and undated (Folder 6: 12)
  - Donetskov, Konstantin, 1953-1960 (Folder 6: 13)
  - Donskaia ermakovskaia stanitsa, New Jersey, 1953 and undated (Folder 6: 14)
  - Donskov, V. V., 1955 (Folder 6: 15)
  - Donskov, Vasilii Semenovich, 1961-1962 (Folder 6: 16)
  - Drobashevskii, Vitalii Petrovich, 1957-1960 (Folder 6: 17)
  - Dronov, Leontii Konstantinovich, 1950-1954 (Folder 6: 18)
  - Dronova, Vera Mikhailovna, 1957-1966 (Folder 6: 19)
  - Drutskoi, Aleksei Aleksandrovich, 1953-1961 (Folder 6: 20)
  - Druzhakin, Georgii Nikolaevich
    - 1951-1959 (Folder 6: 21)
    - 1960-1969 (Folder 7: 1)
  - Dubentsov, Nikolai Konstantinovich, 1957 (Folder 7: 2)
  - Dubiago, Georgii Aleksandrovich, 1953 (Folder 7: 3)
  - Dubina, K. P., 1956 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Dubovskov, A., 1962 (Folder 7: 5)
  - Dukhopol'nikov, Platon Mikhailovich, 1953-1954 (Folder 7: 6)
  - Dukhopol'nikova, Nadezhda Evgen'evna, 1955-1956 (Folder 7: 7)
  - Dvoichenko-Markova, Efrosiniia Mikhailovna, 1955 (Folder 7: 8)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1952-1959 (Folder 7: 9)
  - Efimov, Igor A., 1963 (Folder 7: 10)
  - Efimov, Ivan, 1957 (Folder 7: 11)
  - Efremov, Boris Viacheslavovich, 1952-1959 (Folder 7: 12)
  - Efremov, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1952-1966 (Folder 7: 13)
  - Elatontsev, Semen Georgievich, 1952 (Folder 7: 14)
  - Elatontseva, Lidiia Petrovna, 1955 (Folder 7: 15)
  - Eliseev, Dmitrii Tikhonovich, 1955-1966 (Folder 7: 16)
  - Eliseev, Fedor Ivanovich, 1953-1964 (Folder 7: 17)
  - Emel'ianov, N., 1959 (Folder 7: 18)
  - Emeri, Mariia Aleksandrovna, 1952-1969 and undated (Folder 7: 19)
  - Eremenko, Fedor Zinov'evich, 1952-1953 and undated (Folder 7: 20)
  - Erizhenskii, Ivan Petrovich, 1959 and undated (Folder 7: 21)
  - Ermakov, S., 1954-1956 (Folder 7: 22)
  - Ermilov, Dmitrii Tikhonovich, 1955 (Folder 7: 23)
  - Erokhin, D. G., 1962 and undated (Folder 7: 24)
  - Evtushenko, Mikhail Il'ich, 1957-1958 (Folder 7: 25)
  - Farafonov, Vl., 1966 and undated (Folder 7: 26)
  - Fedorov, Evgenii Afanas'evich, 1966-1967 (Folder 7: 27)
  - Fedorov, Nikolai Vasil'evich, 1952-1967 (Folder 8: 1)
  - Fedorov, Sergei Vladimirovich, 1958 (Folder 8: 2)
  - Fedotova, O., 1960 (Folder 8: 3)
  - Fetisov, Kapiton Petrovich, 1950-1957 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Fialkovskii, Mr., 1954 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Florin, Sergei Nikolaevich, 1959-1966 (Folder 8: 6)
  - Fomin, Aleksandr Fedorovich, 1953-1954 (Folder 8: 7)
  - Fotiev, Sergei Nikolaevich, 1966 (Folder 8: 8)
  - Frolov, Arsenii Porfirovich, 1953 and undated (Folder 8: 9)
  - Gabaev, Vladimir Pringistanovich, 1952-1958 (Folder 8: 10)
  - Gaev, Petr Nikolaevich, 1956 (Folder 8: 11)
  - Gaffari, Z., 1965 (Folder 8: 12)
  - Garaburda, E., 1956 (Folder 8: 13)
  - Garbar, A., 1958 (Folder 8: 14)
  - Gavriil, Archimandrite, 1965 (Folder 8: 15)
  - George, Aleksandra Stepanovna, 1953 (Folder 8: 16)
  - Gerovskii, Aleksei Iul'ianovich, 1953 (Folder 8: 17)
  - Getu, Vikentii Ivanovich, 1964 (Folder 8: 18)
  - Gizhitskii, V. V., 1963 (Folder 8: 19)
  - Glaznov, Mr., undated (Folder 8: 20)
  - Gnedich, Dmitrii Dmitrievich, 1955-1961 (Folder 8: 21)
  - Golitsyn, Vladimir Emanuilovich, 1950-1953 and undated (Folder 8: 22)
  - Golovkov, Mikhail Nikonovich, 1952 (Folder 8: 23)
  - Golovkov, Vladimir Konstantinovich, 1957-1968 and undated (Folder 8: 24)
  - Golubintsev, Aleksandr Vasil'evich, 1953-1962 (Folder 8: 25)
  - Golubov, Mikhail Alekseevich, 1949-1964 and undated (Folder 8: 26)
  - Goncharov, D. and Nikolai Dmitrievich, 1952-1962 (Folder 8: 27)
  - Gontarev, Boris Aleksandrovich, 1952-1953 (Folder 8: 28)
  - Gordeenko, Ivan Nikandrovich, 1953 and undated (Folder 8: 29)
  - Gordeev, Andrei Dimitrievich, 1952-1964 (Folder 8: 30)
  - Gorin, Vasilii Martynovich, 1959 (Folder 8: 31)
  - Gorsko-kazach'ia stanitsa, 1954 (Folder 8: 32)
  - Govalov, Aleksei Petrovich, 1951-1963 (Folder 8: 33)
  - Govorukhin, Ivan Timofeevich, 1954-1955 (Folder 8: 34)
  - Grabbe, Georgii, Reverend, 1956 (Folder 8: 35)
  - Grachev, M., 1953 (Folder 8: 36)
  - Grebenshchikov, I., 1963 (Folder 9: 1)
  - Grekov, Petr Timofeevich, 1953-1955 (Folder 9: 2)
  - Grekov, Vladimir Nikolaevich, 1966 (Folder 9: 3)
  - Grigorii (Borishkevich), Archbishop, 1954-1955 (Folder 9: 4)
  - Grinev, Gennadii Modestovich, 1955-1966 (Folder 9: 5)
  - Grishin, Ivan Gavrilovich, 1953-1968 (Folder 9: 6)
  - Grishin, Viktoriia Aleksandrovna, 1956 (Folder 9: 7)
  - Grondijs, L. H., 1953 (Folder 9: 8)
  - Gul'diev, Petr Danilovich, 1951-1952 and undated (Folder 9: 9)
  - Gusev, Anatolii Mikhailovich
    - 1950-1953 (Folder 9: 10)
    - 1956-1964 (Folder 9: 11)
  - Huxley-Blythe, Peter J., 1955-1959 (Folder 9: 12)
  - Iadov (Yadoff), Oleg Ivanovich, 1955-1958 and undated (Folder 9: 13)
  - Iadova, S., 1953 and undated (Folder 9: 14)
  - Iampol'skii, Pavel Vasil'evich, 1961-1962 (Folder 9: 15)
  - Ilovaiskii, Vladimir Ivanovich
    - 1948-1951 (Folder 9: 16)
    - 1952-1954 (Folder 9: 17)
  - Ilving, Vladimir Mikhailovich, 1953 (Folder 10: 1)
  - Inokov, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1962 (Folder 10: 2)
  - Ioann (Shakhovskoi), Archbishop, 1951-1954 (Folder 10: 3)
  - Iordan, Boris Mikhailovich, 1954-1956 (Folder 10: 4)
  - Iovich, N., 1961-1969 (Folder 10: 5)
  - Ippolitov, Anton Nikiforovich, 1950-1962 (Folder 10: 6)
  - Isaev, Vladimir Mikhailovich, 1954 (Folder 10: 7)
  - Iur'ev, Sergei Vladimirovich, 1958-1960 (Folder 10: 8)
  - Iurikov, P., 1961-1963 (Folder 10: 9)
  - Ivanov, Dmitrii Ivanovich, 1954 (Folder 10: 10)
  - Ivanov, Flor Samuilovich, 1952-1953 and undated (Folder 10: 11)
  - Ivanov, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1954-1958 (Folder 10: 12)
  - Izmailov, N., undated (Folder 10: 13)
  - Kabakov, I., 1956 (Folder 10: 14)
  - Kadoshnikov, Dmitrii Georgievich, 1954 (Folder 10: 15)
  - Kakurin, Ivan Ivanovich, 1954-1967 (Folder 10: 16)
  - Kalmykov, N., 1953-1956 (Folder 10: 17)
  - Kal'fov, Georgii, 1953-1954 (Folder 10: 18)
  - Kal'nitskii, Mikhail Nikolaevich, 1958 and undated (Folder 10: 19)
  - Kamkin, Viktor Petrovich, 1962-1966 (Folder 10: 20)
  - Karanov, Veniamin Borisovich, 1954-1960 (Folder 10: 21)
  - Karasev, Ivan, 1953-1957 (Folder 10: 22)
  - Karasev, Vladimir, 1954 (Folder 10: 23)
  - Karaulov, Iakov Maksimovich, 1962-1963 (Folder 10: 24)
  - Kargal'skaia, Valentina Georgievna and Nataliia Sergeevna, 1958-1960 (Folder 10: 25)
  - Karlash, S. M., 1954-1958 (Folder 10: 26)
  - Karpov, A., 1962 (Folder 10: 27)
  - Karpov, Nikolai Vasil'evich, 1958-1963 (Folder 10: 28)
  - Kashkarov, Pavel Aleksandrovich, 1957 (Folder 10: 29)
  - Kashkin, Sergei Aleksandrovich, 1963-1964 (Folder 10: 30)
  - Kasinskii, Andrei Mikhailovich, 1957 (Folder 10: 31)
  - Kazachenko, Aleksandr Sergeevich, 1954 (Folder 10: 32)
  - Kazach'ia zhizn', 1965 (Folder 10: 33)
  - Kergentsev, Mikhail, 1953 (Folder 10: 34)
  - Khaliunov, V., 1954 (Folder 10: 35)
  - Khandoga, Semen, 1952 (Folder 10: 36)
  - Kharchenko, S., undated (Folder 10: 37)
  - Kharitonov, Afanasii Kuz'mich, 1952 and undated (Folder 10: 38)
  - Kharzhevskii, Vladimir Grigorievich, 1957-1958 (Folder 10: 39)
  - Khlebnikov, Lavrentii Alekseevich, 1953-1954 (Folder 10: 40)
  - Khmelevskii, A., 1960 and undated (Folder 10: 41)
  - Khodnev, Dmitrii Ivanovich, 1956-1957 (Folder 10: 42)
  - Khokhlachev, Nikolai Alekseevich, 1949-1968 (Folder 10: 43)
  - Khokhlacheva, Tamara Stepanovna, 1958-1959 (Folder 10: 44)
  - Khol'mston, A., 195? (Folder 10: 45)
  - Khoperskii, Nikolai Viktorovich, 1960-1966 (Folder 10: 46)
  - Kindeev, D., 1962 (Folder 10: 47)
  - Kisel', Nikifor Lukich, 1957-1958 (Folder 10: 48)
  - Klevtsov, Ivan Romanovich, 1957 (Folder 10: 49)
  - Klimov, S., 1956-1960 (Folder 11: 1)
  - Koliubakin, Ivan Alekseevich, 1953-1954 and undated (Folder 11: 2)
  - Kolesov, Grigorii Naumovich, 1954-1965 (Folder 11: 3)
  - Komarov, Fedor Efimovich, 1952 (Folder 11: 4)
  - Komitet po zashchite Russkoi pravoslavnoi tserkvi v zapadnoi Germanii ot kommunizma, 1962. (Folder 11: 5)
    Includes Soobshcheniia, September 1962
  - Kondratovich, Sergei Lukich, 1956-1960 and undated (Folder 11: 6)
  - Kononov, Ivan Anatol'evich, 1953-1958 and undated (Folder 11: 7)
  - Konstantinov, Petr Filaretovich, 1953 (Folder 11: 8)
  - Kon'kov, Veniamin Grigor'evich, 1954-1956 (Folder 11: 9)
  - Kon'kova, Vera Aristarkhovna, 1955 (Folder 11: 10)
  - Korf, K., 1954 (Folder 11: 11)
  - Korochentsov, Aleksandr Viktorovich, 1948-1950 (Folder 11: 12)
  - Korol'kov, Nikolai Evdokimovich, 1952-1965. (Folder 11: 13)
    Includes Donskoi ataman, No.1597, 1921
  - Korovaev, Boris, 1954 (Folder 11: 14)
  - Korovaeva, N., 1958-1959 (Folder 11: 15)
  - Korzhev, Grigorii Mikhailovich, 1953 (Folder 11: 16)
  - Kosov, Iurii Maksimovich, 1953-1968 and undated (Folder 11: 17)
  - Kostenko, M., 1961 (Folder 11: 18)
  - Kotel'nikova, Irina Vladimirovna, 1962 (Folder 11: 19)
  - Kotov, Evgenii S., 1963 (Folder 11: 20)
  - Kovalenko, P., 1953 (Folder 11: 21)
  - Kovalev, Ivan Ivanovich, 1953-1962 and undated (Folder 11: 22)
  - Koval'chuk, F., 1956 (Folder 11: 23)
  - Kozlov, Sergei T., 1952-1965 (Folder 11: 24)
  - Krasnianskii, Nikolai Ivanovich, 1962-1963 (Folder 11: 25)
  - Krasnin, Vladimir, undated (Folder 11: 26)
  - Krasnov, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1956-1960 (Folder 11: 27)
  - Krasnova, Valentina Aleksandrovna, 1952-1957 and undated (Folder 11: 28)
  - Kravchenko, A., 1960 (Folder 11: 29)
  - Kravchenko, Mariia Dimitrievna, 1952-1954 (Folder 11: 30)
  - Kravchenko, Oleg, 1955 (Folder 11: 31)
  - Kravchenko, V. A., 1955 (Folder 11: 32)
  - Krestinskii, B., 1958 (Folder 11: 33)
  - Kriukov, Ivan, 1954 (Folder 11: 34)
  - Krivoshapko, Zinaida, 1962 (Folder 11: 35)
  - Krivosheev, Anatolii Mikhailovich, 1959-1960 (Folder 12: 1)
  - Krivov, Aleksei Sergeevich, 1957 (Folder 12: 2)
  - Kromkin, Mr., 1959 (Folder 12: 3)
  - Krotov, V., 1965 (Folder 12: 4)
  - Kryzhanov, Arkadii Ivanovich, 1952-1953 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Kucherov, Mikhail, 1953-1958 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Kudash, Nikolai Timofeevich, 1964 (Folder 12: 7)
  - Kudinov, Aleksandr Ivanovich
    - 1953-1959 and undated (Folder 12: 8)
    - 1960-1964 (Folder 12: 9)
  - Kudinov, Nikolai Petrovich, 1952-1963 (Folder 12: 10)
  - Kudrenko, I. M., 1954 (Folder 12: 11)
  - Kulestsov, Mikhail, 1953 (Folder 12: 12)
  - Kulikov, Fedor, 1952-1958 (Folder 12: 13)
  - Kumov, Vasilii Nikolaevich, 1952-1967 (Folder 12: 14)
  - Kunakov, Aleksandr Efremovich, 1963-1968 (Folder 12: 15)
  - Kuprianov, Semen Ignatovich, 1950-1966 (Folder 12: 16)
  - Kurin, Aleksei Mikhailovich, 1958-1959 (Folder 12: 17)
  - Kuritsyn, I., 1958 (Folder 12: 18)
  - Kurochkin, M., undated (Folder 12: 19)
  - Kurylchek, William, 1951 (Folder 12: 20)
  - Kushakov, Grigorii Grigor'evich, 1955-1956 (Folder 12: 21)
  - Kutepov, Boris Nikolaevich, 1952-1954 (Folder 12: 22)
  - Kutyrin, Vladimir Vladimirovich, 1947-1950 and undated (Folder 12: 23)
  - Kuznetchenko, Petr, 1964 (Folder 12: 24)
  - Kuznetsov, Boris Mikhailovich, 1962-1967 (Folder 12: 25)
  - Kuznetsov, Georgii Mikhailovich, 1961-1965 (Folder 12: 26)
  - Kuznetsov, Vasilii Vasil'evich, 1956-1968 (Folder 13: 1)
  - Kviatkovskii, I., undated (Folder 13: 2)
  - Lachugin, Afanasii, 1951-1953. (Folder 13: 3)
    Includes marriage certificate
  - Lampe, Aleksei Aleksandrovich, 1949-1963 (Folder 13: 4)
  - Lanskoi, Illarion Sergeevich, 1956-1957 (Folder 13: 5)
  - Lashin, Andrei Efimovich, 1956-1962 (Folder 13: 6)